Casino Royale is too much for one James Bond!
Casino Royale is a adventure, action, comedy film directed by Joseph McGrath.
Sir James Bond is called back out of retirement to stop SMERSH.
In order to trick SMERSH, James thinks up the ultimate plan -
that every agent will be named 'James Bond'.
One of the Bonds, whose real name is Evelyn Tremble is sent to take on Le Chiffre in
a game of baccarat, but all the Bonds get more than they can handle.
James Bond, played by David Niven.
Evelyn Tremble, played by Peter Sellers.
Vesper Lynd, played by Ursula Andress.
Le Chiffre, played by Orson Welles.
Mata Bond, played by Joanna Pettet.
The Detainer, played by Daliah Lavi.
Casino Royale is a 1967 spy parody film originally
distributed by Columbia Pictures.
It is loosely based on the 1953 novel   Casino Royale, the first
novel in Ian Fleming's James Bond book series.
The film stars David Niven as the "original" Bond, Sir James Bond 007.
Forced out of retirement to investigate the deaths and disappearances of
international spies, he soon battles the mysterious Dr.
Noah and the ruthless counter-intelligence agency SMERSH,
inspired by actual organizations in the USSR.
The film's tagline: "Casino Royale is too much...
for one James Bond!" refers to Bond's plan to mislead SMERSH in which six other agents are pretending to be "James Bond", namely, baccarat master Evelyn Tremble (Peter Sellers); millionaire spy Vesper Lynd (Ursula
Andress); Bond's secretary Miss Moneypenny (Barbara Bouchet); Bond's daughter with Mata Hari, Mata Bond (Joanna Pettet); and British agents Cooper (Terence Cooper) and the Detainer (Daliah Lavi).
Feldman, the producer, had acquired the film rights in 1960 and had attempted to get Casino Royale made as an
Eon Productions Bond film; however, Feldman and the producers of the Eon series, Albert R.
Broccoli and Harry Saltzman, failed to come to terms.
Believing that he could not compete with the Eon series,
Feldman resolved to produce the film as a satire.
The budget escalated as various directors and writers became involved in the
production, and actors expressed dissatisfaction with the project.
Released on 13 April 1967, two months prior to Eon's fifth Bond film, You Only Live Twice, Casino Royale was a financial success, grossing over $41.7 million worldwide, and Burt
Bacharach's musical score was praised, earning him an Academy Award nomination for the song "The Look of Love", performed on the film's soundtrack by Dusty Springfield.
Critical reaction, however, was generally negative, with many
reviewers regarding it as a baffling, disorganised affair.
Since 1999, rights have been held by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer,
distributors of the Bond films by Eon Productions.
The film explores themes of casino, scotland, spy, intelligence, queen.
The tone is lighthearted.